Guide to the Northern Virginia Oral History Project collection, 1958-1996
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 1: Northern Virginia Community, 1958-1983
  - WAGNER, MABEL Family life in Langley, VA (ca. 1890-1970) with emphasis on transportation, the Langley Citizens Association, and local legends 1972, 1 sound cassette (45 min) mono.; 21 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WAGSTAFF, R. EDWARD. The struggle to save Sully Plantation (Fairfax County, VA)during the development of Dulles Airport (ca. 1920-1965) with emphasis on Wakefield Chapel(1850-1972), Part 1 1966, 3 sound cassettes (150 min) mono.; 1 sound tape reel(master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WAKEFIELD, LOWELL T., JR. Family life in Annadale, VA(ca. 1915-1975) with particular emphasis on Wakefield Chapel December 9, 1976, 2 sound cassettes (90 min) mono.; 7 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WALKER, BERTHA BOWMEN (Mrs. Wilbur) Oakton History, David Walker, Chantilly, Church of the Brethren, Dairy farming October 5, 1980, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WALKER, VERNON August 25, 1981, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WATT, GRACE November 11, 1976 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WATT GRACE January 6, 1977 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WEBB, ERNEST E. Family life in Langley, VA(ca. 1910-1960) with emphasis on roads, transportation, and suburbanization February 12, 1972, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono.; 5 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WELLS, ERNEST E. Reminiscences of the City Manager of Falls Church, VA-(ca. 1959-1983) August 2, 1983, 1 sound cassette (60 min) mono.; 1 abstract (3p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WEST, WILLIAM. Black community life in and around Vienna, VA (ca. 1870-1940) with emphasis on Wakefield Chapel(1850-1972), Part 1 October 2, 1974, 1 sound cassette; 72 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WEST, WILLIAM. Community life in Vienna, VA (ca. 1874-1971) October 2, 1974, 1 sound cassette (30 min) mono; 1 sound tape reel(master); 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WEST, WILLIAM. Conversation with William West: race relations, transportation and social life in Vienna, VA (ca. 1900-1920) December, 1965, 30 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WEST, WILLIAM. Life in the back community of Vienna, VA (ca. 1870-1960) September 17, 1974, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 67 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WEST, WILLIAM. A student's and teacher's reminiscences of the black school of Fairfax County, VA (ca. 1875-1955) January 22,1970, 2 sound cassette (90 min.) mono.; 2 sound tape reel (master).; 14 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WILKENS, ANNE. Reminiscences of a member of the Fairfax County (VA) Board of Supervisors with emphasis on government, zoning, and bond issues May 20, 1974, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 25 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WILLIAMS, FRANK E. Oakton History June 16, 1981, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WINSTON, GERTRUDE CHESLEY Education in Fairfax County, VA (ca. 1920-1970)reminiscences of a school teacher May 7,1970, 1 sound cassette (45 min.) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 11 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WOODSON, W.T. Administration of Fairfax County, VA schools (ca. 1929-1961) With emphasis on salaries for teachers September 21, 1969, 1 sound cassette (35 min.) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WOODSON, W.T. Legato School (ca. 1877-1930) a museum in Fairfax County (VA) 1970, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WOODSON, W.T. Reminiscences of the Superintendent of Fairfax County (VA)Schools (ca. 1929-1961) with emphasis on teachers, discipline, and school integration September 17, 1974, 1 sound cassette (50 min.) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WYNKOOP, VIRGIE WELLS. Community life in Vienna, VA (ca. 1890-1960) with emphasis on education November 11, 1977, 1 sound cassette (30 min.) mono.; 10 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - YOUNG, BEULAH A. December 21, 1969, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master).; 67 page transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
- Series 2: Northern Virginia Changes, 1982-1986
  - BATES, MILDRED D. The Navy School and other schools in Pender, VA (ca. 1920-1940) May 6, 1970, 1 sound cassette (11 min.) mono.; 1 sound tape reel (master); 1 abstract (1p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BENNETT, MABEL Family life in Fairfax, VA (ca. 1910-1980) December 6, 1982, 1 sound cassette (35 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - BACKUS, FLORENCE with CLYDE SHEPHERDSeptember 30, 1984., 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CHOPEK, JOSEPH B. Of the Little River Management Company, March 19, 1985, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CLAY, EDWIN S. III. Director of Fairfax County Libraries. February 17, 1989., 1 sound cassette; transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - COSTON, OTIS "SKIP". September 3, 1985, 1 sound cassette; transcript. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - CURTICE, CUBA. July 11, 1985, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DAY, ANNA S. Family life in Dranesville, VA-(ca. 1915-1974) July 7, 1983, 1 sound cassette (60 mi.) mono.; 1 abstract (5p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DONN, JAMES. with Joseph Ellis. February 3, 1984, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - DURHAM, C.J.S.(JACK). Community life in Great Falls, VA (ca. 1927-1983)Discussion of Durham's government service career and the restoration of his home, the 223 year old "Towlston Grange" March 13,1983, 2 sound cassette (105 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (5p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ELLIS, JOSEPH. Work, family, and community life in the black community of Dranesville, VA. (ca. 1910-1980) December 2, 1982, 2 sound cassettes (90 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (5p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ELLIS, JOSEPH. with James Donn. February 3, 1984, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FARRELI, GERTRUDE S. Family and community life in Falls Church, VA (ca. 1917-1980)with emphasis on transportation, the Depression, and government jobs. December 9, 1983, 2 sound cassette (90 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (4p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FELTON, GEORGE W. August 30. 1984, 1 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - FOOTE, EVELYN P. Brig. General at Ft. Belvair. July 13, 1989, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GERALD, BILL. December 27, 1985, 1 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GOTTHARDT, VIOLA SHREVE. Reminiscences of a long time Dunn Loring, VA resident (ca. 1915-1980) December 2, 1982, 2 sound cassette (90 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (4p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GREEAR, VIRGINIA McFARLAND. Family life in Floris and Herndon, VA (ca. 1900-1982)with emphasis on education, church activities, the Great Depression, and World War II October 21, 1982, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.;1 abstract (3p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - GUINEE, JOHN. February 4, 1982, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HAWKES, DEAN ROBERT T. April 17, 1990, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HAZEL, JOHN T. December 27, 1985, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - HOGUE, JANET. Burke Center. January 1, 19862, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - JESSUP, GEORGIA. October 20, 1986, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - KEATING, GLADYS. August 2, 1984, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - KEPHART, HERMAN. Community life in Herndon,(ca. 1920-1930)with emphasis on Dulles Airport, Herndon Female Seminary, and the Great Depression November 4, 1982, 2 sound cassettes (90 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (3p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - KIELSGARD, FRED. Burke Center. August 14, 1985, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - KIELSGARD, FRED. July 1984, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LEWIS, AMOS, L Community life in Vienna, VA (ca. 1936-1960) with emphasis on land acquisition and development November 10, 1982, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LEWIS, JOHN G. October 11, 1984, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - LUKENS, HORACE C. Community life in Vienna, VA (ca. 1940-1982) with emphasis on the Vienna Presbyterian Church October 20, 1982, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MAGNESS, WILLIAM. August 31, 1981, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MATTHEWS, FRANK. June 28, 1984, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MCCULLOCH, MARY K. February 2, 1989, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MILLARD (family). 100th Anniversary of Colvin Run Mill Ownership. October 9, 1983, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MOORE, PATRICIA. Burke Center. January 3, 1986 (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MILLARD (family). 100th Anniversary of Colvin Run Mill Ownership. October 9, 1983, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MILTON, PETERSON. Burke Center Partnership. August 13, 1985, 2 sound cassettes (only tape 2 available) (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - MULLADY, BERNARD R. December 13, 1983, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - OLIVER, WILLARD. Community life in Great Falls, VA (ca. 1910-1982) with emphasis on place name changes within Fairfax County October 20, 1982, 2 sound cassette (90 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (5p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - POTTER. Franconia. September 13, 1984, 1 sound cassette (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - RISSEED. Burke Center Partnership. August 20, 1985, 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ROBINSON, LAURES C. Life in the black community of Centreville, VA (ca. 1895-1982) with emphasis on family relationships; with Lillian Robinson. March 24, 1983, 2 sound cassettes (70 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (5p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - ROBINSON, LILLIAN. Life in the black community of Centreville, VA (ca. 1895-1982) with emphasis on family relationships; with Laures C. Robinson March 24, 1983, 2 sound cassettes (70 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (5p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - RYAN, ROBERT. Reston September 2, 1981, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SEELEY, MARTHA. Family Life in McLean, VA (ca. 1927-1983) with emphasis on the family home, "Maplewood" March 24, 1983, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (4p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SHARPER, D. MANN. About October 1951. September 22, 1983, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SHEPHERD, CLYDE with FLORENCE BACKUSSeptember 30, 1984., 2 sound cassettes (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - SHREVE, EUGENE G. Reminiscences of a life long resident of Falls Church, VA (ca. 1890-1945) with emphasis on transportation and suburbanization November 18, 1982, 2 sound cassette (90 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (3p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - STEINBAUER, FRAN. Reston Land Corps. January 28, 1981, 2 sound cassettes. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - STUTZ, PAM. Burke Center. December 11, 1985, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - VAN PATTEN, CHARLES H. Community life in Great Falls, VA (ca. 1923-1983) with emphasis on the operation of Colvin Run January 12, 1983, 1 sound cassette (60 min.) mono.; 1 abstract (2p.). (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WELCH, FRANKIE. June 28, 1988, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WHITESDIES, WILLIAM. February 9, 1989, 1 sound cassettes. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
  - WOODS, R. LANGDON. February 13, 1985, 1 sound cassette. (Oversize TC 3 Vault)
- Series 3: Transcripts, 1962-1983
  - Transcripts, 1962-1983 (Box 1)
  - Transcripts, 1962-1983 (Box 2)
- Series 4: Northern Virginia Leadership Project, 1990-1996
  Note that these box numbers are not the same as the box numbers for Series 3.
  - Brault, Abe, August 14, 1990 (Box 1-3)
  - Campbell, Elizabeth, May 16, 1996 (Box 1-3)
  - Hazel, John T. "Til", April 27, 1993 (Box 1-3)
  - Hirst, Omer, July 14, 1990 (Box 1-3)
  - Lynch, Ed, July 6, 1990 (Box 1-3)
  - Miller, Helen Hill, July 31, 1990 (Box 1-3)
  - Prichard, Edgar, August 8, 1990 (Box 1-3)
  - Williams, Carrington, June 19, 1996 (Box 1-3)
  - Wood, John "Jack", August 19, 1990 (Box 1-3)